# **Owen Martin**

3850 Paseo del Prado Apt 36 • Boulder, CO 80301
303-325-6880 • martin.owen22@gmail.com • owingit.github.io
"The place to improve the world is first in one's own heart and head and hands, and then work outward from there." -Robert Pirsig



# Overview

I am enthusiastic about learning, an experienced software engineer in test, and a passionate outdoorsman. I love challenges and grasp new problems quickly, and can effectively communicate complicated ideas in simple language. I have experience in research labs at CU Boulder and Tufts University and in software development at large hybrid cloud companies in Boston and Boulder.

# **Experience**

#### NetApp

# December 2018 - Present

<u>Software Engineer in Test</u> with the SolidFire group. Currently designing and developing reliable, scalable, and maintainable test automation to validate complex features of the NetApp Hybrid Cloud storage backend.

I was the lead developer behind the effort to automate virtual network testing for NetApp's latest stack release and serve as an admin reviewer for the test code base. I also built an intelligent scheduler that syncs with the organization's release schedule to trigger Jenkins test runs on a prioritized cadence.

# BeingSattvaa

#### December 2018 - Present

<u>Freelance Web Developer</u> Created and modernized web presence for Singapore-based startup. Features added include HTTPS support; secure booking with iChronoz; and automatic emailing, in addition to content maintenance and SEO optimization.

#### Hitachi Vantara

#### August 2017 - September 2018

<u>Software Quality Engineer</u> on the HCP-Anywhere team. Improved quality best practices through design and implementation of novel reviewboard integration with in-house test tracking software; streamlined test processes via scriptwriting, automating tests, and automating deployment of test environments

# **Tufts University**

## January 2015 - May 2017

<u>Teaching Assistant</u> for the Data Structures (COMP-0015) class. Designed and deployed new in-person grading techniques for sorting algorithms project; tutored students in asymptotic complexity, data structures concepts and applications, and programming fundamentals; hosted collaborative grading groups with other TAs to improve the CS department's grading consistency, transparency, and accountability.

# University of Colorado - Boulder

#### May 2015 - August 2015

<u>Research Assistant</u> in the Martin Lab studying antibiotic resistant bacteria in the local watershed. Designed and deployed an interactive website tracking locations of native resistance; designed my own experiments; documented reproduction steps.

## Research

# Bee Trophollaxis with Correlated Random Walks

## February 2019 - October 2019

Research assistant in the Peleg lab simulating bee movement within hives as correlated random walks with varying degrees of deviation to understand the connectivity of a hive system

#### **Technology and International Migration**

#### February 2015 - June 2015

As part of an international development hackathon, I built a web application for the location and distribution of useful resources, designed for the refugee population of Lesvos, Greece. Following that I pivoted my project to a research paper on tech-for-justice hackathons around the world and their relative benefits to the migrant community.

## **Computer Simulation of Liquids**

## September 2013 - April 2014

Undergraduate computational chemistry research in the Lin group at Tufts University designing algorithms for particle-particle interaction

#### **Education**

## **Tufts University**

August 2013 - May 2017

Bachelor's of Science - Computer Science

Coursework in CS: Algorithms • Data Structures • Theory of Computation • Machine Structure and Assembly Language Programming • Computational Biology • Web Programming • Data Mining • Artificial Intelligence • Discrete Math • Linear Algebra • Structure and Function of Complex Networks • User Interface Design • Computing for Developing Regions

Other Coursework: Multivariable Calculus • Organic Chemistry • Differential Equations • Creative Writing x<sub>3</sub> • Linear Models in R (edX) • Convolutional Neural Networks in Python (Coursera) • Earth Data Analytics (CU Boulder Earthlab) • Deep Learning in Python (Udemy)

#### **Technical Skills**

- 1. Data Analytics and Simulations 2. Development
- Languages | Packages: Python R SQL Processing | scikit-learn pandas PyTest NetworkX matplotlib tidyverse numpy scipy NetLogo sqlalchemy Dash
- 2. <u>Languages | Software</u>: Python Java Javascript C++ C HTML5/CSS php SQL Groovy go | vmware git Docker JIRA/Confluence Jenkins PostgreSQL MS Office Linux, Windows, Mac OS

# Leadership

# NetApp Solidfire, Admin Code Reviewer

#### December 2019 - Present

I gatekeep code quality to Solidfire's test code repository called Valence. I read thirty to forty code reviews a week and provide feedback, constructive criticism, and maintainability advice to engineers across many teams.

## Hitachi Intern Program, Mentor

## April 2018 - August 2018

Taught, mentored, and facilitated the professional development of two summer interns, both current undergraduate students. Under my guidance, one of the interns exceeded productivity levels of several full-time employees on my team.

#### **Tufts Wilderness Orientation, Leader**

# August 2014 - May 2017

Guided groups of incoming first-year students on weeklong backpacking trips in the White Mountains of New Hampshire, with a co-leader, representing the school and working to embolden and empower first-year students